JAMES ROSKELL

Poulton-le-Fylde - FY6 7EJ Email: <u>JamesRoskell1@yahoo.com</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

A motivated and organised individual with a passion for game and software development. Having gained a degree in Software Engineering Game Development, I have experience with C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and C++. Knowledgeable in project work with particular focus in game development and programming, having created a gaming platform using Unity and Unreal, and a QR code as a marketing tool during the course work placement. Excellent abilities working as part of a team as well as individually with skills in Microsoft, and Programming, with experience of VS Studio Code. I have a vision to create accessible websites for internet users.

CORE SKILLS

- Microsoft Packages
- ◆ Teamwork
- ♦ Reliable
- ◆ Time & Workload Management
- ♦ Organisation
- ♦ Technological Passion
- Programming
- Game creation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ◆ Unity Game Engine
- ♦ C++
- **♦** C#
- JavaScript
- ♦ HTML
- ♦ CSS
- ♦ MySQL
- ♦ Monogame

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Delivery Driver

May 2022 - Present - My Hermes (Evri Lifestyle Couriers)

Responsible for collecting parcels from the depot and delivering them as addressed. I book routes and follow company policy in delivery, including scanning parcels using an electronic device. I comply with Health & Safety and Data Protection, and ensure all parcels are delivered in a timely manner and intact.

Software Engineer

Mar 2022 - May 2022 - GatherAid (Formerly MyChariti)

Responsible for developing a social networking app geared towards charities and supporters/donors. Working remotely and as part of a team to enhance the online features for the homepage and using Bubble to code. Attention to detail applied where checking for bugs and ensuring the front end presents well for UI. Project organisation through the Trello app, and communication using Slack which assists with the remote working.

Online Retail Inputter

Jan 2017 - Present - Oxfam, Poulton Le Fylde

Responsible for researching the valuations of items for sale within an ecommerce capacity. I input and upload high value donated items onto the charity's online website ensuring the correct pricing for products. I maximise income by utilising Oxfams online presence to inform customers with descriptive titles and product information to sell goods, as well I ensure detailed photographs of each item. I maintained inventory of each item posted and sold, recording these appropriately and following procedures. Furthermore, through my researching skills, I have been responsible for increasing the online presence and income over the last 6 months.

Office Assistant

Sept 2016 – Jan 2017 - British Heart Foundation, Blackpool.

Responsible for ensuring all customer receipts were filed away alphabetically following the organisations data protection policy and GDPR procedure. I also supported staff in administrative tasks including archiving receipts and documents held for a 3year period.

QUALIFICATIONS

University Centre; Blackpool and Fylde College: Sept 2019 – May 2021. Software Engineering Game Design (BSc Hons) 2:2 Degree

University Centre; Blackpool and Fylde College Sept 2019 – May 2020. Software Engineering Game Design Foundation Degree

Projects:

- Work Based Learning
 - Programmed and created a platform game called 'Avoid the Deadlines' using Unity, which is a fun and easy game to navigate to attract students on to the course.
 - Developed a marketing tool for a local church, a QR code to print on their booklets & notice board for parishioners to scan with their mobile devices to navigate to their social media page.
- ♦ Group Project
 - Created a platform-based game with Unity called 'Finna', I integrated Audio and a User Interface of the health bar as well as supporting with design for each level.

Blackpool and The Fylde College – Sept 2017 – June 2018 Level 3 Computing – Distinction GCSE English – C GSCE – Maths - D

<u>ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS</u>

Digital Skills Award – May 2021; Blackpool & Fylde College.

HOBBIES & INTEREST

I am an avid Ebay seller with an interest in ecommerce, I enjoy the process of selling items, developing my photography skills and gaining an understanding of online marketing. I enjoy keeping updated on technological and IT information and have an interest in web design. I am a keen gamer, who enjoys adventure type games.

REFERENCES

Sara Marie Bramwell, Oxfam, Poulton Le Flyde. 01253 894548. oxfamshopf1036@oxfam.org.uk

Lee Holroyd, University Centre; Blackpool & The Fylde College. 01253 352352. lhol@blackpool.ac.uk